<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tennis | Qiong Wu]]></title>
  <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/categories/tennis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-01T15:25:12-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://creasyw.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qiong Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strategic Playing for the First Several Sets]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/03/01/strategic-playing-for-the-first-several-sets/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T14:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/03/01/strategic-playing-for-the-first-several-sets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is worth noting that yesterday I had my first win in the 3.0 league=D 7-5, 3-6, and 10-6 in the tie-breaker set. In today’s lesson, Bob told me a bit more about strategic playing. It was all about probing different aspects of the opponent.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Keey hitting in the middle (or either left or right) as long as I can, and see what is the tolerance of the opponent – whether him or me would get frustrated first and try to make some change.</li>
  <li>Consistently push either his backhand or forehand within a point.</li>
  <li>Driving the ball from side to side and observe the pattern of his transition – does he have a high successful rate for the ground stroke? Is forehand-to-backhand better or worse than the backhand-to-forehand? Does he tend to hit cross court or staight to the baseline?</li>
</ul>

<p>The advanced version will combine the timing of pushing towards the net and volley, but I haven’t got there yet… I am still struggling to position myself in the transition of volley, let alone the judgement of lobbing or cut-across from my opponent… So, there is a long way to go(:</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
