<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tennis | Qiong Wu]]></title>
  <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/categories/tennis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-27T07:48:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://creasyw.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qiong Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3.0 League for the Third Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/07/17/3-dot-0-league-for-the-third-time/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/07/17/3-dot-0-league-for-the-third-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are two dimensions for a court. I just kept forgetting it! It is always worthwhile to explore both left/right and mid/back of the court. As an amateur like me, the most struggling part might be forced to constantly adjust the tempo. I should keep pushing in this kind of manner more often.</p>

<p>It is almost always a wiser choice to stick to the “percentage shot” for both forehand and backhand. I had too many unforced errors hitting down the line. However, on the other hand, when I stand in the middle of the court, I should be more comfortable to change the direction. For most of the opponents, they would struggle more in their backhands. So I could try more inside-out.</p>

<p>I have a better volley technique, but am still awful in both timing and positioning. I can serve with more power, and a little bit more consistent. The next step will be taking more control in direction. Besides, I need to prepare earlier/higher and hit with looser wrist for the ground stroke. I also need push the momentum forward when I hit the ball. It’s almost one year since I learned this activity, but I still cannot master its most basic part…</p>

<p>Well, anyhow =D</p>

<p>[UPDATE 20/07/2014: I just had a big victory this afternoon: 6-1 and 6-2, against the guy who used to beat me twice. Although it would never be a big deal for winning or losing an amateur game, I still feel really happy for that. I have more control for percentage shot and decrease unforced errors a lot.</p>

<p>Aiming higher in the net also could push opponent further away from the court, then have a better chance receiving a shallow response, and then move into the court, hit down the line, and move forward more for volley – this is a right sequence from building to ending a point. Deep balls with strong top spin would seldom be a good chance to change the direction. Instead, just hit cross court and try to be as deep as I can, meanwhile aiming bouncing towards the baseline rather than the side line.</p>

<p>Maybe it’s really useful to keep thinking both during the match and afterwards, it makes me evolve stronger; or maybe my exercises of lower body and core muscles finally pay out; or maybe my resting and eating schedule give me more energy to do the movements right; or more possibly, my opponent just had a bad day. Well…</p>

<p>I love this game, both mentally and physically(:  ]</p>

<p>[UPDATE 24/07/2014: Lost a game. However, anyway, the take-way points are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Prepare earlier.</li>
  <li>Be patient. Anyone could make mistakes in any time.</li>
  <li>Be relax when serving.</li>
</ul>

<p>]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinetic Chain of Reactions]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/kinetic-chain-of-reactions/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T23:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/kinetic-chain-of-reactions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Ideally, every time hitting the ball should be a “kinetic chain of reactions”– the momentum moves from feet to knee, to waist, to shoulder, and finally to the forearm and wrist.</li>
  <li>If I only use part of the chain, I might still hit a good ball, occasionally. But it would consume more energy, and the hitting would be much more unstable.</li>
  <li>Technically speaking, serve is the only way that I can completely control this kinetic chain, because I can control all of the paces and do not need to move around.</li>
  <li>During a point, whenever opponent hits the ball, I should pause and split feet, no matter where I am in the court. This could help me make judgment. More importantly, it is the way to “load energy” and start the “kinetic chain”.</li>
  <li>I have too many aspects to improve, but this might be the most important one.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thought Process in a Tennis Match]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/04/12/thought-process-in-a-tennis-match/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-12T13:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/04/12/thought-process-in-a-tennis-match</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Thursday, I had another win in the league(: In my point of view, I was pretty lucky for the previous victories, but I did have an overwhelming victory this time. I was much better than one month ago (yeah! of course=P), and the opponent was a sub-player, who was weaker than others in the league. Although he had a strong surfing, both his forehand and backhand were not so good. The responses were soft and shallow with only a little bit back spin, which gave me a wide angel to hit either inside-in or inside-out.</p>

<p>When I talked with my coach yesterday, he provided some valuable insights about how I should consider the process of a match</p>

<ul>
  <li>Keep the feet floating while preparing ground stroke.</li>
  <li><strong>Volley is the only way to end a point</strong>. No matter how aggressive the ground strokes are, they are not considered to end the point. Instead, they just <em>build</em> the point. If it ends, let it be. If not, that’s the normal case. It means I should always prepare for the next stroke. And the sad part of the story is that after nine months I still don’t really know how to end a point……</li>
  <li>Do not get frustrated playing with players who consistently send lofty backspin. If he voluntarily hands over the control of pace, I should use it wisely: add more topspin on the returns; actively change the angel; don’t rush to end the point but patiently build it.</li>
  <li>Prepare earlier: decide to use forehand or backhand based on the trajectory; once decided, prepare for the ready position; after the bounce, I should begin the movement of hitting; the center of gravity should put into the front halves of the feet, and always keep the momentum forward while hitting the ball.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strategic Playing for the First Several Sets]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/03/01/strategic-playing-for-the-first-several-sets/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-01T14:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/03/01/strategic-playing-for-the-first-several-sets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is worth noting that yesterday I had my first win in the 3.0 league=D 7-5, 3-6, and 10-6 in the tie-breaker set. In today’s lesson, Bob told me a bit more about strategic playing. It was all about probing different aspects of the opponent.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Keep hitting in the middle (or either left or right) as long as I can, and see what is the tolerance of the opponent – whether him or me would get frustrated first and try to make some change.</li>
  <li>Consistently push either his backhand or forehand within a point.</li>
  <li>Driving the ball from side to side and observe the pattern of his transition – does he have a high successful rate for the ground stroke while moving? Is his forehand-to-backhand better or worse than the backhand-to-forehand? Does he tend to hit cross court or staight down to the line?</li>
</ul>

<p>The advanced version will also include the timing of pushing towards the net as well as volley, but I haven’t got there yet… I am still struggling to position myself in the transition of volley, let alone the judgement of lobbing or cut-across from my opponent… So, there is a long way to go(:</p>

<p>[Update March 7] The control of my ground stroke is nice, but the hitting point is far from optimal – I should keep the racquet a little bit “closer” and the hitting point should be a little bit in front while the racquet rising in its maximum speed and facing towards the net. Still, The target zone is “higher in the net”.</p>

<p>[Update March 15] The way to increase spin is to make the preparison faster and to prepare the racquet a little bit lower–all movements should be done before the bonuce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
