<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tennis | Qiong Wu]]></title>
  <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/categories/tennis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-10T21:32:50-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://creasyw.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Qiong Wu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tennis Progress in October]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/10/01/tennis-progress-in-october/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-01T09:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/10/01/tennis-progress-in-october</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oct. 1st. Private Lesson</p>

<ul>
  <li>The wrist for my forehand stroke is too tight. That is why I lost my power control. The right manner should relax the wrist in a <em>“controlled”</em> way, so as to gain the directional control as well as the power/spin control.</li>
  <li>It should be cautious to do the inside-out forehand stroke. That is, I have to leave enough time so that my whole body could arrive at the right position and then change my momentum from moving sideway to pushing forward. Or the return ball would sail away. On the contrary, preparing the backhand stroke needs less time, and now I do perform consistent backhand strokes. Hence, using strokes from both hand side no matter whether I am in the due side or ad side.</li>
  <li>I love the drill of “15 mid-court balls”. It’s a combination of cardio, toning, and quick attacking.</li>
  <li>The closer to the net, the shorter swing for the strokes.</li>
</ul>

<p>Oct. 8. Private Lesson</p>

<ul>
  <li>I can barely do the backhand back spin right, and now find that the forehand back spin is even harder. I should use more of my body momentum and fully extend my arm to the direction of returning so as to give the ball more penetration.</li>
  <li>Why do I always forget to split the feet as the opponent hit the ball?!</li>
  <li>The footwork of volley is similar to those of ground strokes–for the forehand side, I should do 2-steps stroke starting from right foot first. This would give me more foreword momentum.</li>
  <li>It is the same for the backhand side. The 1st step starting from the left foot should cut the angle rather than simply moving sideway, so that I could gain more forward power from the body movement.</li>
  <li>My recovering position should be more near the center for the forehand side, and recover much faster for the both sides… It is not hit-and-look-then-recover. Regardless my returns are legal, I should change my position according to my direction of return. This would give me much more time to prepare for the next shot.</li>
  <li>For the duel-side approach shots, it is better not to hit cross court, unless the opponent is far away from that side. Because it requires me to change the direction of moving and run quite a long distance to the left to response the next ball. In the contrary, if I hit down the line, I only need to go on running to the net.</li>
  <li>On the other hand, if the mid-court ball is in the middle between duel and ad sides, I can do whatever is right to deal with it.</li>
</ul>

<p>Oct. 9. Drill at ATC.</p>

<ul>
  <li>I have much better volleys when I keep my feet on the ground and move towards the coming ball. It is a good start to master how to end the point:)</li>
  <li>My ground stroke is off tempo for whatever reason… And I do not turn my body enough to generate the momentum driving the ball.</li>
  <li>I should get a little bit closer to the base line when I recover the position–half feet or one feet behind the base line might be a good distance. Prepare to moving forward at any time.</li>
</ul>

<p>Oct. 10. Gym.</p>

<ul>
  <li>It feels really nice get up at 5:30 and eating breakfast at 8 after hard workout.(:</li>
  <li>The modified version of <em>“bend over row”</em> that I watched in the <a href="http://youtu.be/T0LjSFng_ek?t=1m12s">Chauncey Billups NBA Fit</a> is good. It exercises the core, shoulder, and back muscles.</li>
  <li>When I watched the Shanghai Rolex Masters, I saw Djokovic had the really developed back and shoulder muscles. That might be a focus for my recent workouts.</li>
  <li>I also had a conversation with coach Bob. He prioritized the sections as first for core, second for lower body, and third for the upper body, in which the back and should should come before the chest and arms.</li>
  <li>I won’t do the full HIIT routine recently, but I should revisit it in the winter.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tennis Progress in September]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/09/10/tennis-progress-in-september/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-10T22:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/09/10/tennis-progress-in-september</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sep. 9th. Tennis Club</p>

<ul>
  <li>Dealing with high-bounce top-spin balls, the feet should keep on the ground if possible. More importantly, the racket should be a little bit more open than the regular ground stroke, so that the response won’t hit the net.</li>
  <li>When I am running back, hit the ball higher.</li>
  <li>On the other hand, keep body momentum moving forward while hitting. If time is sufficient, turn body for both forehand and backhand stroke. This is similar to boxing, where the most powerful shot is generated by the whole body, not only just arms and shoulders.</li>
</ul>

<p>Sep. 10th. Private lesson.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Begin serving from the Ad-side.</li>
  <li>Toss the ball 45 degree towards the net.</li>
  <li>Toss higher.</li>
  <li>Bend knees is not just a gesture, but is for pushing the body upwards.</li>
  <li>Relax the wrist as much as I can.</li>
  <li>For practice, try to put two feet close to each other first, and then combine the movement of right foot from the regular position to the left foot.</li>
</ul>

<p>Sep. 13th. Mini-Match vs. Dylan</p>

<ul>
  <li>When I am trying to save the ball from backhand, the racket should fact “largely” to the other side rather than to the sky. Stay relatively at the same height of the touching point and push it, not chop it.</li>
  <li>After serving, instead of observing whether the bounce is valid, quickly retreat behind the base line.</li>
  <li>If there is no time to go back to the most comfortable hitting zone, just prepare early, relax wrist, and swing the racket after the bouncing point. There is a good chance I could still hit an acceptable return.</li>
</ul>

<p>Sep. 16th. Mini-Match vs. Eric.T.</p>

<ul>
  <li>It felt so nice that I am almost (or close to) as competent as one of the coaching staff one year ago in the very beginner class. Maybe it was because I could not push him to the fullest extent as what he did to me in the match. But, whatever, I had four games ending with multiple deuces, and I did won one of them. One is always a good start:)</li>
  <li>He cared less about the “percentage shoot” than what I did, but he would observe my movements and always tried to hit the open court. This would be my goal in (hopefully) three months.</li>
  <li>My serving is relatively stable now. I need to relax more, both physically and mentally, for both shoulder and wrist; to catch the ball a little bit higher; and to push it more upwards and forwards. Plus right direction of tossing and more practice, I could at least stop bleeding in my serving games.</li>
  <li>There are too many pieces missing from my repository. I am thinking to master back spin as the next step–for defense as well as changing the tempo of the match. After that, I will revisit ground stroke, transition from back court to mid-court, volley/over-head, and then serving again. All of them might take another month and a half. After that, I will seek a re-match with Eric and see how will that go.</li>
</ul>

<p>Sep. 18th. Private lesson and Drill</p>

<ul>
  <li>Learned how to do the backhand back spin:
    <ul>
      <li>To prepare, I should REALLY turn the body sideways. Use the left hand help to hold the racket.</li>
      <li>Prepare the racket a little bit higher. The slightly downwards movement will help to prevent the response floating much.</li>
      <li>The length of swing is longer than what I am used to for the double-handed backhand. So, swing early.</li>
      <li>The contact point is farther away from the body, so I should not over run or need to leave enough room for the swing.</li>
      <li>Relax the shoulder but not turn the waist too much. Meanwhile, lean body towards the net. That is, the majority of the force should be forward rather than to the right side.</li>
      <li>The face of racket should also face mainly towards the net.</li>
      <li>If possible, follow through the racket to the right side to give the ball more side spin.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>When I did the volley, I should never jump at the same time.</li>
</ul>

<p>Sep. 21th. Match with Reazul.H. (5-6, 7-6)</p>

<ul>
  <li>I’ve lost to this guy three times in a row in the league. So, I am really glad that today’s result could demonstrate my progress.</li>
  <li>His strategy puts defense in the 1st priority, waiting for me to earn the point or to make an unforced error. I have the controlled strokes for the most of the match. That’s great.</li>
  <li>When I can put the 1st serve in, the serving game becomes really easy to keep. In the 2nd set, maybe because of the tired, I have to breath really hard and to exhale out loud while serving. It actually helps me to keep the rhythm right. Of course, other points also hold: relax wrist, toss 45 degree in front of the body, toss high, bend knees and lift the whole body up, touch the ball in the highest point and push it upwards and forwards.</li>
  <li>I have several good drop shots and overhead hits, but those are not consistent. I need to work on it more. Exploring the 2D of the court is always worth trying–for consuming the opponent’s energy and disrupting his typo.</li>
  <li>Back spin by backhand does not work for most of the time…</li>
  <li>I should not retreat way back in the court unless the opponent has really good and strong top spin. Pushing forward is beneficial to enlarge the hitting angle and to put pressure to the other side. This is actually the only way to end a point. However, to achieve it, I need to prepare much earlier and turn sideways to add spin, and do the volley right–follow the route of the return, pause and split before the opponent hits the ball, keep both feet on the ground, and push the ball to the OPEN COURT!</li>
</ul>

<p>Sep. 25. Private lesson. 2-sets Match with Allen (3-6, 6-3)</p>

<ul>
  <li>Double-handed backhand should drive the racket to draw the logo of Nike. This would help me prepare a little bit higher, and have a smoother movement with better topspin. Two caveats are that I should begin the movement <em>earlier</em> since it takes longer time, and make the face of racket <em>less</em> open.</li>
  <li>I used to loose my wrist too much for the forehand ground stroke. I shouldn’t let the head of racket drop that much. Instead, I should use more of my arm/body movements to create the topspin. When I correct my movement, I can feel more of the directional control, but less of the power control–I overhit plenty of balls with the right direction. Maybe I should close more of the face of the racket, or it means that I do not provide enough spin. <em>I need to figure it out</em>.</li>
  <li>For the backhand backspin, I should extend my right arm to follow through the movement and use more of my right shoulder.</li>
  <li>My forehand volley “mysteriously” becomes better. During practice, I could easily drive the ball to either inside-in or inside-out. The backhand could still only do the inside-in. However, that is the practice. I ALWAYS forget to <em>split then react</em> during the match. It might be the reason that I find myself jumping while volley. So, do exactly what you practice for the match!</li>
  <li>The match was tough, and every game might easily go either way. I should figure out a solution during the match much quicker, and drive him running around the court more.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Third Season of 3.0 Ends Up with 2nd Place]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/08/30/third-season-of-3-dot-0-ends-up-with-2nd-place/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-30T10:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/08/30/third-season-of-3-dot-0-ends-up-with-2nd-place</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was better than I expected:)</p>

<p>The main changes came from a few simple suggestions of my coach: keeping patient in rally; making percentage shoots and reducing unforced errors as many as possible; warming up longer than I used to; and balance myself while serving. That was it.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, I suppose my working out in gym also pays off. Several months ago, I started to divide the strength training to smaller parts as upper/lower/core body, along with cardio exercise. For each part, there are several different approaches to work out. Specifically for tennis, the back and core muscles are more important than those of chest and shoulder for ground strokes. A little bit exercises for the forearm could improve the penetration of serving a lot. Lower muscles are much much more important than I expected–they could provide more explosive strength, let running faster, and more importantly, protect the knee joints. Besides, pilate and stretch are indispensable parts for every workout. These last-30-minutes cooling down process help the body relax and keep up with everyday’s progress.</p>

<p>Of course, I still have plenty of REALLY weak aspects, such as lousy serving, bad backspin and volley, and getting lost in the mid-court…</p>

<p>Anyway, I am happy to get this level:) and wish myself could be the champion one day.</p>

<p>[UPDATE] 09/03/2014. I just saw the greatest match in this year, Murray vs. Djokovic. There are some interesting facts.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Both of them slided their feet together while hitting the serving, but when I did that way, my upper body would become unstable which in turn makes my serving even worse…</li>
  <li>Percentage shoots are the mainstream responses, and they would more inclined to approach to the net when hitting down the line.</li>
  <li>Both of them use lots of backspin for defense, but their movements seemed to have more “chopping” than I did. And if I did that way, the ball would float very high and sail…</li>
  <li>Drop shots are effective means to explore the depth of the court. Making the opponents running is almost always a good strategy to disrupt the tempo as well as actively draining off the energy.</li>
  <li>Mental toughness is the key to win the match.</li>
</ul>

<p>[UPDATE] 09/09/2014. I won’t sign up for any 3.0 League in this year since I’ve began to play the tournament in the university. It has less challenging mentally, but more physically. The strategic play is still useful, but I would also expect longer rally and have more cadio-/HIIT training correspondingly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3.0 League for the Third Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/07/17/3-dot-0-league-for-the-third-time/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-17T10:47:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/07/17/3-dot-0-league-for-the-third-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are two dimensions for a court. I just kept forgetting it! It is always worthwhile to explore both left/right and mid/back of the court. As an amateur like me, the most struggling part might be forced to constantly adjust the tempo. I should keep pushing in this kind of manner more often.</p>

<p>It is almost always a wiser choice to stick to the “percentage shot” for both forehand and backhand. I had too many unforced errors hitting down the line. However, on the other hand, when I stand in the middle of the court, I should be more comfortable to change the direction. For most of the opponents, they would struggle more in their backhands. So I could try more inside-out.</p>

<p>I have a better volley technique, but am still awful in both timing and positioning. I can serve with more power, and a little bit more consistent. The next step will be taking more control in direction. Besides, I need to prepare earlier/higher and hit with looser wrist for the ground stroke. I also need push the momentum forward when I hit the ball. It’s almost one year since I learned this activity, but I still cannot master its most basic part…</p>

<p>Well, anyhow =D</p>

<p>[UPDATE 20/07/2014: I just had a big victory this afternoon: 6-1 and 6-2, against the guy who used to beat me twice. Although it would never be a big deal for winning or losing an amateur game, I still feel really happy for that. I have more control for percentage shot and decrease unforced errors a lot.</p>

<p>Aiming higher in the net also could push opponent further away from the court, then have a better chance receiving a shallow response, and then move into the court, hit down the line, and move forward more for volley – this is a right sequence from building to ending a point. Deep balls with strong top spin would seldom be a good chance to change the direction. Instead, just hit cross court and try to be as deep as I can, meanwhile aiming bouncing towards the baseline rather than the side line.</p>

<p>Maybe it’s really useful to keep thinking both during the match and afterwards, it makes me evolve stronger; or maybe my exercises of lower body and core muscles finally pay out; or maybe my resting and eating schedule give me more energy to do the movements right; or more possibly, my opponent just had a bad day. Well…</p>

<p>I love this game, both mentally and physically(:  ]</p>

<p>[UPDATE 24/07/2014: Lost a game. However, anyway, the take-way points are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Prepare earlier.</li>
  <li>Be patient. Anyone could make mistakes in any time.</li>
  <li>Be relax when serving.</li>
</ul>

<p>]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinetic Chain of Reactions]]></title>
    <link href="http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/kinetic-chain-of-reactions/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T23:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://creasyw.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/kinetic-chain-of-reactions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Ideally, every time hitting the ball should be a “kinetic chain of reactions”– the momentum moves from feet to knee, to waist, to shoulder, and finally to the forearm and wrist.</li>
  <li>If I only use part of the chain, I might still hit a good ball, occasionally. But it would consume more energy, and the hitting would be much more unstable.</li>
  <li>Technically speaking, serve is the only way that I can completely control this kinetic chain, because I can control all of the paces and do not need to move around.</li>
  <li>During a point, whenever opponent hits the ball, I should pause and split feet, no matter where I am in the court. This could help me make judgment. More importantly, it is the way to “load energy” and start the “kinetic chain”.</li>
  <li>I have too many aspects to improve, but this might be the most important one.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
